Emma Hyun Jung Ham

Software Developer & Web Developer

Info

Address

6 Bowman Road, Auckland, 0620, New Zealand

Phone

02108216229

Email

emma.hj.ham@gmail.com

Links

Portfolio: https://emmaham-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

Linked In: linkedin.com/in/emmaham

github:github.com/ham8821

Skills

PHP Programming

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Java Programming

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

• • • •

AJAX, JQeury

• • • •

MvSQL

• • • •

Flexibility and Adaptability

• • • •

Git, version control tool

 \bullet \bullet \bullet

Business Analysis

 \bullet \bullet \bullet

Profile

A self-directed Software Engineering student with hands on experience on developing web applications from db scratch(MySQL) to deployment(AWS, DevOps), specializing in high-level programming and software management. Extensive real-environment programming experience in PHP, Java, web development technologies (HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, J Query etc) as well as high proficiency in user interface design and management.

A naturally curious, persistent, quick learner who understand how to work together as a team, always keen to learn new things and willing to learn good attributes from others.

Project

Online sales and stock management Web Application

Project achievement

- Solving business problem in targeting online customers by delivering solid and desirable online web service.
- knowledge of software development and programming with understanding of initial flow covering from database designing to testing to deliver the product.
- · High understanding of programming language such as PHP, MySQL
- Comprehensive knowledge of modern development technology such as HTML,
 CSS, JavaScript, J query, Ajax, bootstrap 4 ,git, azure DevOps and deployment technology such as AWS(Amazon Web Service)

Second-hand item shopping website

Developing a platform where users can sell and buy second-hand products,

Project achievement

- How to cope with pressure, aiming to deliver the outcome within limited time frame(10 weeks).
- Excellent understanding of SDLC, utilizing business knowledge from bachelor's degree in Business Administration for better trouble shooting and avoiding scope creep.
- Web development technology such as PHP, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, web development tools, MySQL server, workbench, bootstrap

Critical thinking and problem solving

• • • •

React

• • • • •

TypeScript

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

Rest API

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

Languages

English

• • • •

Korean

• • • •

Hobbies

Learning modern technologies Most recent learning interest: React.js, TypeScript, Node.js, REST API

Market inventory system

Aug 2018 - Sep 2019 Personal project

Developing a system designed to keep the track of inventory and delivery statue as well as reports for admin.

Project achievement

- Being knowledgeable in programming language such as Java
- Confident in using development environment such as net beans, visual studio code
- Initial understanding of testing flow using J unit test, J testing

Employment History

Project web developer, Liquor Library Ltd New Zealand

Apr 2019 - Present ♀ Auckland

- · Development and maintenance of official websites
- Gained experience in web development
- Extensive teamwork and version management

Part-time barista, hip group Ltd New Zealand

- Assessing customers' needs and preferences, remembering over 150 customers's name to offer better customer experience.
- Tolerance in busy pace working environment and establish a strong bond within a team
- Effective communication skill in multi-cultural environment.

Academic tutor in private institute of Academic support, Educoach Ltd Korea

Jul 2017 - Jul 2018

- Increase the number of enrolled student by 20%, making A+ grade from employee assessment
- Academic support, Developing Effective lesson plans.
- Communication effectively with different age range of student

Extra-curricular activities

Microsoft Accelerator, Microsoft sponsored

As a participant of Microsoft Accelerator Program, having opportunities to learn modern Microsoft development tools and form a group to build a project related to the technology taught in previous phase.

learning achievements

- Microsoft Azure(Cognitive services): Emotion detecting AI to track users' emotion and derive outcome
- React.js web app: Using TypeScript that uses Microsoft Azure
- · Database and RESTful Web API

Best business case in New Enterprise Centre Programme 2019, Ecentre Massey

Internships

Research Assistant Intern, Aon Hewitt

Empowering the content and the idea of the project based on market analysis skill and presenting skill, making project successful at the end of the term.

IT Summer intern, Ministry of Economic Affairs

Analyzing database using relational diagrams, organizing all the information from individuals by sorting and analyzing to issue proper statistics based on right insight on job market.

Education

Aspire2 International, Information Technology Graduate Diploma lv7

Web Programming: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX, PHP, MySQL, Java Programming, ,programming concepts, systems development Industry Project working with an Auckland client

Jeju National University, bachelor's degree in Business Administration

References

References available upon request